Guide to the Microwave Research Institute Technical Reports RG.031
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
Guide to the Microwave Research Institute Technical Reports
1942-1970
RG.031
Poly Archives & Special Collections at Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology
39.0 Linear feet
Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Microwave Research Institute.; Weber, Ernst; Physics
- Series I: Report numbers PIBMRI 0-100, 1942-1945
  - Junction Effect of Two Unequal Matched Coaxial Lines, PIBMRI-2-42, 1942 September; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-2-42)
  - Theory of Coaxial Attenuators, PIBMRI-8-42, 1942 September 21; Griemsmann, John W. E.; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-8-42)
  - Lossless Coaxial Exponential Tapers, PIBMRI-15-43, 1943 May 20; Peskin, Edward; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-15-43)
  - Notes on the Use of Bolometers for Ultra-High Frequency Attenuation Measurements, PIBMRI-22-43, 1943 June 2; Ebert, John (Volume PIBMRI-22-43)
  - The 1B2 Bolometer Terminal, PIBMRI-23-43, 1943 June 11; Ebert, John; Johnson, Stanley; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-23-43)
    Armed Services Technical Information Agency (U.S.).
  - P.I.B. Metallized-Glass Attenuators and Miscellaneous R.F. Test Accessories, PIBMRI-43-44, 1945 April; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-43-44)
  - Frequency Sensitivity of Metallized-Glass Attenuator Inserts Type TMS-4PB, PIBMRI-79-45, 1945 May 11; Nelson, Harry C. (Volume PIBMRI-79-45)
  - Conference on Metallized-Glass Plate Program at P.I.B. Research, PIBMRI-84-45, 1945 May 22; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-84-45)
  - Accuracy of Attenuation Measurements Made with the Ballantine Voltmeter, PIBMRI-85-45, 1945 May 30; Nelson, Harry C. (Volume PIBMRI-85-45)
  - Microwave Resistance Comparator, PIBMRI-86-45, 1945 May 22; Ebert, John (Volume PIBMRI-86-45)
  - Frequency Sensitivity of Metallized-Glass Attenuator Inserts Type TMS-3PB, PIBMRI-87-45, 1945 May 20; Nelson, Harry C. (Volume PIBMRI-87-45)
  - The TMX-16 PB Metallized-Glass Plate for X-Band Fixed Attenuator, 25 db, PIBMRI-89-45, 1945 June 2; Giordano, Anthony B.
  - The TMX-24 PB Metallized-Glass Plate for X-Band Fixed Attenuator Pads of 10 db and 13 db, PIBMRI-91-45, 1945 June 26; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-91-45)
  - A Resistive Variable Attenuator for K-band with 40 db Maximum Attenuation, PIBMRI-92-45, 1945 May 31; Ebert, John; Johnson, S. (Volume PIBMRI-92-45)
  - Electrical Performance of Metallized-Glass Attenuators for TS-147/UP in Extended-X-band PIBMRI-93-45, 1945 July 6; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-93-45)
- Series II: Report numbers PIBMRI 101-200, 1945-1949
  - Precision Metallization of Glass, PIBMRI-103-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-103-45)
  - Fixed Value Metallized-Glass Coaxial Attenuators, PIBMRI-104-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-104-45)
  - Variable Metallized-Glass Coaxial Attenuators, PIBMRI-105-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-105-45)
  - Metallized-Glass Bolometers, PIBMRI-106-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-106-45)
  - The Development of Metallized-Glass Attenuating Elements for X--Band Wave Guide, PIBRMI-107-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBRMI-107-45)
  - Metallized-Glass Wave Guide Attenuators, PIBMRI-108-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-108-45)
  - The Development of Metallized-Glass Attenuators for Test Set TS-147/UP, PIBMRI-109-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-109-45)
  - R-F Components for Microwave Bridges, PIBMRI-110-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-110-45)
  - Microwave Power Measurement with Bolometers, PIBMRI-111-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-111-45)
  - Type "N" Connector Design and Tests, PIBMRI-112-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-112-45)
  - Microwave Attenuation Standards, PIBMRI-113-45, Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-113-45)
  - Microwave Attenuation Measurement, PIBMRI-114-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-114-45)
  - Development of Miscellaneous R-F Line Components, PIBMRI-115-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-115-45)
  - Precision Metallized-Glass Resistor Units, PIBMRI-116-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-116-45)
  - Final Report for OSRD Contract OEMsr-335 Sponsored by NDRC, Division 14, Project No. 15.02, PIBMRI-117-45, 1945 October 31; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Graduate Electrical Engineering Department.. (Volume PIBMRI-117-45)
  - Basic Aspects in the Design of Cut-Off Attenuators, PIBMRI-120-46, 1946 Februrary 11; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-120-46)
  - Quarterly Report on Research and Development of Attenuators Over the Frequency Range of 8,200 mc/sec. to 39,000 mc/sec. for the Period of June - August 1950, PIBMRI-125.29-50, 1950 September 20; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-125.29-50)
  - VSWR Measurements on Type "N" Cable Connectors from 2.5 to 10.0 Kilomegacycles per Second, PIBMRI-136-46, 1946 November; Griemsmann, John W. E.; Nadler, Leo (Volume PIBMRI-136-46)
  - Response of Thermionic Vacuum Tubes Under Uniform Emission to Applied Signal Voltages, PIBMRI-135-47, 1947 February 18; Gamble, Edward H. (Volume PIBMRI-135-47)
  - Source Distribution Functions for Small High Gain Antennas, PIBMRI-137-47, 1947 April 4; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-137-47)
  - Method for Improving Resolution in a Two Dimensional Scanning Process, PIBMRI-138-47, 1947 April 7; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-138-47)
  - Synthesis of Lossy Microwave Structures for Broad Band Matching with Applications to the Design of Coaxial Attenuators, PIBMRI-139-47, 1947 March 31; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-139-47)
  - Impedance Description of Planar Gratings, PIBMRI-140-47, 1947 April; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-140-47)
  - The Design of Wide-Band Coaxial, Fixed Pad Attenuators for the Frequency Band 4,000 to 10,000 No/sec., PIBMRI-141-47, 1947 April 3; Carlin, Herbert J.; Fox, Arnold, M. (Volume PIBMRI-141-47)
  - Theoretical Study of Metal Film Water Calorimeter for Microwave Power Measurements, PIBMRI-142-47, 1947 April; Kahal, Robert (Volume PIBMRI-142-47)
  - Influence of Current Flow and Magnetic Fields During the Formation of Thin Metallic Films by Evaporation, PIBMRI-143-47, 1947 April 18; Schleuning, Hubert W. (Volume PIBMRI-143-47)
  - A Note on MRI Performance, PIBMRI-147-47, 1947 May 7; DiToro, Michael J. (Volume PIBMRI-147-47)
  - Analytical and Experimental Study of Magnetic Amplifiers, PIBMRI-149-47, 1947 June 10; Stateman, Murray (Volume PIBMRI-149-47)
  - Bibliography Report on Phase (A) of Contract No. N60R1-98, Task Order IV, PIBMRI-150-47, 1947 June 23; Gold, Bernard (Volume PIBMRI-150-47)
  - On the Representation and Measurement of Wavelength Discontinuities, PIBMRI-151-47, 1947 June; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-151-47)
  - Bibliography Report on Phase (C) of Contract No. N60RI-98 Task Order IV, PIBMRI-153-47, 1947 June 23; Stateman, Murray (Volume PIBMRI-153-47)
  - Transients in Frequency Modulation, I. Frequency Pulse Applied to Ideal Band Pass Filter, PIBMRI-154-47, 1947 July; Gold, Bernard (Volume PIBMRI-154-47)
  - Transients in Frequency Modulation, II. The Response of a Discriminator Type Network to a Frequency Step, PIBMRI-154.1-47, 1947 September 26; Gold, Bernard (Volume PIBMRI-154.1-47)
  - Transients in Frequency Modulation, III. The Solution of Steady State Problems in Frequency Modulation, PIBMRI-154.2-48, 1948 October 21; Gold, Bernard (Volume PIBMRI-154.2-48)
  - Transients in Frequency Modulation System with Monotonic Phase Distortion, PIBMRI-155-47, 1947; Edelberg, Seymour (Volume PIBMRI-155-47)
  - A Harmonic Generator for the 10,000 MC/SEC to 12650 MC/SEC Frequency Range, PIBRMI-156-47, 1947 July; Nelson, Harry C. (Volume PIBRMI-156-47)
  - Waveguide Circuit Theory: Coupling of Waveguides by Small Apertures, PIBMRI-157-47, 1947 July; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-157-47)
  - A Calibrated Heterodyne Receiver for Micro-Wave Attenuation Measurements, PIBMRI-161-47, 1947 September; Nelson, Harry C. (Volume PIBMRI-161-47)
  - Operation of the Summation of Type Wattmeter Bridge, PIBRMI-164-47, 1947 November 6; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBRMI-164-47)
  - A Direct Reading D-C Bridge for Microwave Bolometer Power Measurements, PIBMRI-165-47, 1947 December 29; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-165-47)
  - Attenuation Characteristics of a Tapered Dielectric Coaxial Attenuator, PIBMRI-167-48, 1948 October 15; Blass, Judd; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-167-48)
  - Preliminary Bibliography on Impedance Measurements, PIBMRI-168-48, 1948 April 7; Oliner, Arthur A. (Volume PIBMRI-168-48)
  - V.S.W.R. Data on B.N.C. Connectors for the Frequency Range 2.4 to 10 KMC/SEC (An Types UG88/U, UG89/U, And UG306/U), PIBMRI-169-48, 1948 May 4; Griemsmann, John W. E.; Nadler, Leo (Volume PIBMRI-169-48)
  - Interim Report on Electromagnetic Theory Applied to Radiation Problems for the Period from 1 May 48 to 31 May 48 Radiation from Slots, PIBMRI-171.1-48, 1948 June; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-171.1-48)
  - Report on 1. Evaluation of Bolometer Errors in The Measurement of Attenuation Using a Bolometer Detector 2. Construction of a Bolometer Element for Waveguide 1/2" x 1/4" x .040", PIBMRI-172-48, 1948 June; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-172-48)
  - A Survey of Phase Changers Used in the Microwave Region, PIBMRI-175-48, 1948 August 30; Altschuler, Helmut M. (Volume PIBMRI-175-48)
  - Report on 1. Vibration Test of 2 x 1.064 Guide Size Glass Attenuator Plates 2. Preliminary Test of the Above Plate Mounted in a Casing, PIBMRI-176-48, 1948 August 4; Schleuning, Hubert W. (Volume PIBMRI-176-48)
  - Analytical Study of an Unbiased Bridge Type Magnetic Amplifier, PIBMRI-177-48, 1948 November 19; Stateman, Murray; Weber, Ernst (Volume PIBMRI-177-48)
  - The Natural Frequency of Vibration of a Glass Plate Attenuator, PIBMRI-179-48, 1948 August 24; Schleuning, Hubert W. (Volume PIBMRI-179-48)
  - Analysis of Small A-C Signal Response of a Space-Charge-Limited Parallel-Plane Diode Having an Oxide Cathode, PIBMRI-180-48, 1948 September 10; Dalman, G. Conrad (Volume PIBMRI-180-48)
  - The Construction and Operation of Broadband Bolometer Powermeters for 20 to 10,000 MC/SEC and 25 μw - 5w, PIBMRI-181-48, 1948 September 8; Carlin, Herbert J.; Torgow, Eugene (Volume PIBMRI-181-48)
  - Steady State Response of Physical Networks to a F.M. Wave, PIBMRI-182-48, 1948 October 26; Brogan, J. (Volume PIBMRI-182-48)
  - The Impedance of a Narrow Lossy, Inductive Obstacle in a Rectangular Waveguide, PIBMRI-184-48, 1948 December 16; Edelberg, Seymour (Volume PIBMRI-184-48)
  - A Short 3/8" Line-to-7/8" Line Precision Broadband Adapter, PIBMRI-148-49, 1949 March 21; Albanese, Victor; Griemsmann, John W. E. (Volume PIBMRI-148-49)
  - A Study of Directional Couplers with Emphasis on Frequency Characteristics, PIBMRI-187-49, 1949 January 20; Tanenbaum, Morton S. (Volume PIBMRI-187-49)
  - VSWR Data on H.N. Connectors for the Frequency Range 1.0 to 10.0 KMC./SEC. (AN Types UG 59A/U, UG 60A/U, UG 21/U, UG 333/U, UG 334/U and UG 495/U, PIBMRI-189-49, 1949 April 22; Griemsmann, John W. E.; Nadler, Leo (Volume PIBMRI-189-49)
  - Quarterly Report on Microwave Interference Investigations for the Frequency Range 1,000-40,000 MC/SEC for the Period of November 1, 1948 to January 31, 1949, PIBMRI-192.1-49, 1949 February 21; Griemsmann, John W. E. (Volume PIBMRI-192.1-49)
  - The Representation, Measurement, and Calculation of Equivalent Circuits for Waveguide Discontinuities with Application to Rectangular Slots, PIBMRI-193-49, 1949; Marcuvitz, Nathan (Volume PIBMRI-193-49)
  - Final report of Improved Impedance Measuring Methods Over the Frequency Range of 100 to 10,000 mc/sec, PIBMRI-195-49, 1951 June 5; Altschuler, Helmut M.; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-195-49)
  - Measurement of Waveguide Impedances with a Circular Side Arm, PIBMRI-195-49, 1949 March 14; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-195-49)
  - Steady State Analysis of a Magnetic Amplifier, PIBMRI-196-49, 1949 April 13; Esselman, Walter; Smith, Edward J. (Volume PIBMRI-196-49)
  - Tests of High Power Coaxial Loads for Microwave Powermeters, PIBMRI-198-49, 1949 April 26; Tanenbaum, Morton S. (Volume PIBMRI-198-49)
  - A Broadband High Power Microwave Attenuator, PIBMRI-199-49, 1949 April 25; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-199-49)
  - Bolometer Measurement of Microwave Power Over Broad Frequency Bands, PIBMRI-200-49, 1949 April 25; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-200-49)
- Series III: Report number PIBMRI 201-300
  - The Construction and Operation of Broadband Bolometer Meters for 1,000-10,000 MC/SEC and 5 Watts-1,000 Watts, PIBMRI-201-49, 1949 April 26; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-201-49)
  - Tests Performed by the Microwave Research Institute on Powermeter ME - 19 (XW-1)/U to Satisfy Requirements of Contract W33-038-ac-13848, PIBMRI-202-49, 1949 April 25; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-202-49)
  - Tests Performed by the Microwave Research Institute on Powermeter ME - 20 (XW-1)/U to Satisfy Requirements of Contract W33-038-ac-13848, PIBMRI-203-49, 1949 April 25; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-203-49)
  - Tests Performed by the Microwave Research Institute on Powermeter ME - 20 (XW-1)/U to Satisfy Requirements of Contract W33-038-ac-13848, PIBMRI-204-49, 1949 April 25; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-204-49)
  - Final Report on the Development of Powermeters Over the Frequency Range 20 Mc/sec to 10,000 Mc/sec and 25 μw to 1,000 Watts, PIBMRI-205-49, 1949 April 26; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-205-49)
  - Development of Metallized-Glass Attenuators for Waveguide Size 2" x 1" x 0.064", PIBMRI-206-49, 1949 May 6; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-206-49)
  - Magnetic Amplifier Core Properties Phase (C), PIBMRI-207-49, 1949 May 13; Benjamin, Fred (Volume PIBMRI-207-49)
  - Report on Phase I of the Study of Data Transmission, General Theory of Communication, PIBMRI-208-49, 1949 July 13; Laemmel, Arthur (Volume PIBMRI-208-49)
  - Oxide Cathode Resistance and Rectifying Characteristics, PIBMRI-209-49, 1950 January 12; Dalman, G. Conrad (Volume PIBMRI-209-49)
  - Final Report on the Development of Broadband Microwave Attenuators for Navy Contract NObs-28376 Issued in 2 Sections, Section I - Coaxial Line Attenuators, PIBMRI-217-49, 1949 May 26; Carlin, Herbert J. (Volume PIBMRI-217-49)
  - Final Report on the Development of Broadband Microwave Attenuators for Navy Contract NObs-28376 Issued in 2 Sections, Section II - Rectangular Waveguide Attenuators, PIBMRI-218-49, 1949 May 25; Giordano, Anthony B. (Volume PIBMRI-218-49)
  - Final report NObs 28372 (Issued in Two Volumes) Volume I: Radio Frequency Cable Connector Measurements and Developments, PIBMRI-219-49, 1949 June 10; Griemsmann, John W. E. (Volume PIBMRI-219-49)
- Series VI: Report numbers PIBMRI 301-400
  - The Reactance of a Symmetrical Pair of Strips in Rectangular Waveguide, PIBMRI-1158-63, 1963 April 23; Lewin, L (Volume PIBMRI-1158-63)
    Air Force Cambridge Research Laboratories.
  - Scattering and Propagation of Electromagnetic Waves in Bounded Parametrically Modulated Media, PIBMRI-67-1374, 1968 June; Peng, S. (Volume PIBMRI-67-1374)
    Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. Department of Electrophysics.
  - Research Forecasts in Electronics for the Office of Naval Research, PIBMRI-69-006, 1969 July; Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn. (Volume PIBMRI-69-006)